

https://wandark.github.io/cv/

# SERGIO ANTONIO VALENZUELA BALLESTEROS

#### PROFILE

With more than ten years of experience in IT as a Business Analyst and Technical Consultant for various markets. Proven experience with customer management, problem solving, ability for interpersonal and intercultural relationships with deep knowledge in decision analysis, requirements, business support, risk analysis and critical route. Flexibility and perseverance when new challenges arise.

#### **SKILLS**

- Focused on the business and its customers
- Communication and teamwork.
- Innovate mind
- Analysis and obtaining requirements
- Business and customer support

- Decision analysis
- Hardware Management
- Handling various tools
- Volunteer to take on challenges
- Advanced English language

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Consultant / Product Owner.

GrupoAssa, Now Globant Chile – Jun 2020 – To date.

Contractor for Equifax for the migration of their product Cyber Financial 9c on the cloud.

#### Main Assignments:

- Scrum Methodology
- Document functional requirements for the migration.
- Configuration on the system for each tenant (Client).
- Reviewing and analysis of scripts
- AWS and PGAdmin DB systems usage
- Inductions to new employee and operations
- Atlassian Systems Jira, Confluence.

#### **BUSINESS ANALYST**

Wipro Limited / Chile – Jan 2019 – Sep 2019

Contractor for LATAM Airlines, with the aim of implementing the new Air Freight System (CROAMIS) which replaces the current system it occupies.

#### **Main Assignments:**

- Prepare Workshops of requirements with customers in relation to their needs in the Air Cargo area.
- Generate functional documents based on requirements, business and interface processes.
- Provide training and system demonstrations to customers and end users at different

locations.

- Review of training material and user manuals.
- Develop business scenarios and test cases for the system.

#### **TECHNICAL CONSULTANT**

SOVOS/ Chile - Mar 2018 - Jan 2019 / eleven months

Responsible for the implementation of the e-invoicing system for customers in Latin America and Europe. My role is to coordinate and implement the system, enable communication between the ERP system and RTC (Real Time Connector)

#### Main Assignments:

- Coordinating meetings with the client, in order to explain the system deployment process, this involves pre-verifying the configuration of the servers and validating that there are no inconveniences at the time of installation.
- Installing the system, installing and configuring PSTN software, installing and creating databases in SQL Server, creating tables. Verify the link between the SAP system (or any other similar module) and PSTN.
- Design sheets, based on the customer's requirements, the form of the electronic documentation that you want to process (invoices, credit or debit notes, etc.) the designs are made in used XML C# and Jasper Reports, depending on the platform.
- Testing and Production Period. A constant communication with the client is maintained during the testing period, being contingency in case of an unforeseen event or some error that may be generated. After testing, the production phase begins in which you have to be in an observation process for a week and as in QA you must be prepared for any contingency. The customer then passes into the hands of the support team.

#### **Professional Achievements:**

- In charge of consolidating the information, creating a documentation portal that helped the steps of installation and configuration of the PSTN system as well as documentation in case of errors that could be generated during the deployment.
- Creating an application that generated scripts semi-automatically, which helped us when creating the tables in SQL, some clients had a very weak remote connection and by connecting to them the slower the system installation, especially when writing the SQL query, this application allowed us to generate the queries more quickly and easily which generated a time saving of 50% when installing.
- I was named Team Lead of a group of 4 people, and was also in charge of making inductions when new elements arrived in the area.

## **ASSOCIATE TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER**

ORACLE / Chile - Sep 2011 - Oct 2017 / six years, one month

Responsible for case review for the automation system performing flow quality control, system alarm review for proper routing, maintaining open communication with the professionals in charge of the developed at the time of detection of failures at the global level, reporting weekly the proper functioning of the process.

#### **Main Assignments:**

- Participate in the implementation of the automation process for the MY ORACLE SUPPORT platform, where SRs (Service Requests) were processed and managed with the aim that these SRs reach a repository where in the first instance they should be processed manually to finally manage to automate them.
- Review daily alerts entering the automated flow to verify if the alarm actually failed in the process or was a program error. If the problem was real, the SRs were sent to their corresponding area for resolution.
- Responsible for managing the SRs that were generated minute by minute, designating themto the different agents during the shift.
- In charge of receiving and processing SR, depending on your severity and type of alarm, various solutions (send engineer to the ground or hardware office) frequent contact with the customer should be included and establish an impeccable SLA. Using the tools that would serve to automate the system in the future, each of these SRs were processed for final diagnosis.
- In charge of delivering weekly reports auditing all SRs processed during the week, in this way we were able to obtain resolution patterns that were similar based on the amount of SR processed, this allowed us to document that information and send it to the developers to improve the automated system.
- Responsible for the Disk area of SUN Microsystems for Automation, generate reports regarding SRs that arrived because of Disk problems either for field or office support.
- Quality Control Analyst, after the implementation of the automated system, I was responsible for the quality control of the system, processing SR, investigating new ways to automate alarms, RCA.

#### **Professional Achievements:**

- Audit application, develop an application that allowed to distribute in a more orderly and fast way the large amount of SR that they had to review day by day. With this tool, you can streamline the analysis in the correction of automation processes.
- Responsible for updating customer scripts, directing a group of 3 people, these scripts were essential because it updated customer information which served for automation dispatches.
- I co-responsible for the diagnostic files with the changes made via automated process, with this action I allowed to keep up to date the interventions with the users.

#### **TECHNICAL SUPPORT**

Rotter & Krauss / Chile – May 2010 – Sep 2011 / one year, five months

Responsible for maintaining hardware and networks in each of the stores across the country.

#### **Main Assignments:**

- Remotely fix errors generated by the collection system on Linux in each of the stores, allowing stores to realize their sales without losing customers.
- Plan and install hardware and networks in store openings, so I managed to have everything enabled and functional for the openings of the premises.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- ITIL Foundation (2011)
- Solaris 10 Operating System
- SQL Essentials Bootcamp
- Web Development Bootcamp
- Project Management Fundamentals

# **EDUCATION**

## **ENGINEER IN COMPUTER SCIENCE.**

Diego Portales Professional Institute, Chile

2005 - 2008